我的姓是谢尔顿
Wo de zing shi sheldon.
不  应该是
Non, c'est...
我的名字是谢尔顿
Wo de ming zi shi sheldon.
这算什么?
What's this?
你不是这么做的嘛
That's what you did.
我以为在某些语言里
I assumed, as in a number of languages,
手势也是短语的一部分
That the gesture was part of the phrase.
不是
Well, it's not.
我又怎么知道?  作为老师  你有义务
How am I supposed to know that? as the teacher, it's your obligation
把个人习惯从教学过程中排除
To separate your personal idiosyncrasies from the subject matter.
你知道  我真的很高兴你决定学习普通话
You know, I'm really glad you decided to learn mandarin.
-为什么?  -一旦你学得溜了
-why? -once you're fluent,
你就又多了十几亿的人去烦  而不是来烦我
You'll have a billion more people to annoy instead of me.
梅毒驴子
Mei du lui zi.
你刚才叫里奥纳德是个得了梅毒的驴子
You just called leonard a syphilitic donkey.
向你道歉
My apologies,
我的水平只是和老师一样好
I'm only as good as my teacher.
你为什么要学中文?
Why are you learning chinese?
我认为四川菜馆故意用
I believe the szechuan palace has been passing off
香橙鸡丁来假冒陈皮鸡丁  所以我要去对峙
Orange chicken as tangerine chicken and I intend to confront them.
如果我是你  我会更关心
If I were you, I'd be more concerned
他们是拿什么假冒了鸡丁
About what they are passing off as chicken.
-我要用一下你们的窗户  -随意
-i need to use your window. -sure, go ahead.
不要脸的  你落了ipod
Hey, jerk face, you forgot your ipod!
-怎么了这是  -我来告诉你这是怎么了
-what's going on? -i'll tell you what's going on.
那自恋的蠢蛋把我们的性生活写进了博客里
That stupid self-centered bastar wrote about our sex life in his blog.
去死吧  你个自恋的蠢蛋!
Drop dead, you stupid self-centered bastard!
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧  我们讲到哪儿了
Okay, where were we?
别急  我要先搜索一个博客
Not now, I have a blog to find.
天才也性感 第一季 第17集 (本季完)
The Big Bang Theory S01E17
潘妮  你还好吧
Penny, are you okay?
我很好  里奥纳德  你走吧
I'm fine, leonard. just go away!
我知道分手会让人很难过...
I understand that breaking up with someone can be very painful...
-给我走!  -好吧  开心点  再见
-go away! -okay, feel better! bye!
她不想说话
She doesn't want to talk.
没什么惊讶的  潘妮的情感来自于
Not surprising. penny's emotional response is originated
最原始的脑部  也就是扁桃形结构
In the primitive portion of the brain, known as the amygdala.
然而话语功能处于最后发育的
While speech is centered in the
新大脑皮质中心位置
Much more recently developed neo-cortex.
前者可以轻易统治后者
The former can easily overpower the latter,
科学已经证实这就是
Giving scientific credence to
"无话可说"的概念
The notion of being "rendered speechless."
或者她就是不想说话
Or maybe she just doesn't want to talk.
看  我捡到了一个ipod
Look, I found an ipod!
都摔得不成样子了  你打算怎么处理
It's smashed beyond repair. what are you gonna do with it?
还能怎么办  贴个"九成新"的标签上eBay卖了
What else? sell it on ebay as "slightly used."
是潘妮男朋友的  他们分手了
It was penny's boyfriend's, they broke up.
很显然  他把他们私人生活的细节放在了
Apparently, he posted intimate details of their physical relationship
他的博客上  可我却怎么都找不到
On his blog which I cannot find anywhere.
我要回去再试着和她聊聊
I'm gonna go back and try talking to her again.
好主意  坐在她身旁
Good idea, sit with her.
抱着她  安慰她
Hold her, comfort her.
如果你觉得时机不错
And if the moment feels right,
看看可不可以趁虚而入
See if you can cop a feel.
我才不会趁人之危  霍华德
I'm not going to do that, howard.
我倒完全没意识到现在
I'm not aware of a new social
有什么要求你进行干预和调解的社交习俗
Convention that requires you to intervene at all.
那么处在痛苦中的少女呢
What about damsel in distress?
12世纪骑士的行为准则?  又不是现在
Twelfth century code of chivalry? not exactly current.
你还必须要先成为骑士才可以这么做
You'd also have to be knighted for that to apply.
我才不管  她很难过  我要过去
I don't care. she's upset, I'm going over there.
记得在手上坐一会  让它们暖和一点
Remember to sit on your hands a bit, so they're warm.
我是她朋友
I'm her friend.
我不会在她正脆弱的时候去利用她
I'm not going to take advantage of her vulnerability.
你的意思是  如果在绝望之极时
So you're saying, if in the depths of despair,
她主动向你投怀送抱
She throws herself at you and demands you take her,
当时当下  你就头不回走人?
Right there, right now, you'll just walk away?
我说我是她朋友  又不是同志朋友
I said I'm her friend, not her gay friend.
听着  我知道你不想说话...
Listen, I know you said you didn't want to talk...
-我不想  -对不起
-i don't. -sorry.
-等等  -等等?  你说"等等"?
-wait! -wait? did you say "wait"?
跟我说实话
Tell me the truth.
我是不是那种整天跟大混蛋在一起的傻瓜
Am I just an idiot who picks giant losers?
那么我就是跟好人在一起  然后把他们都变成了混蛋
So I pick good guys but turn them into losers.
当然不是
of course not.
非此即彼  到底是哪个
It's gotta be one or the other. which is it?
抱歉  是哪两个选项来着?
I'm sorry, what were the choices again?
我真的以为麦克与众不同
I really thought mike was different.
我以为他...
I thought he was...
体贴  又聪明
Sensitive and smart,
我不是指你那种聪明  是普通不吓人的那种
I mean, not you smart, normal non-freaky smart.
是  是  当然
Yeah, no, sure.
现在他跑过来羞辱我
And then he just goes and has to humiliate me
在博客上写些关于我的东西让全世界的人来看
By writing about me on his blog so the entire world can read it.
跟你说吧  那博客不容易被找到的
I tell you, it's not all that easy to find.
真的?  跟我要好的同事看到了  我姐姐看到了
Really? my friends at work found it, my sister found it.
从电子邮件来看  一些在密歇根州
Judging by my email, a number of prisoners
监狱里的牢犯也看到了
At the michigan state penitentiary found it.
那家伙究竟写了什么
What exactly did this guy write?
我不是说想知道你性生活的细节  只是想...
Not that I need to know the details of your sex life. I just thought...
算了
Never mind.
不用
No, you know what?
你可以去看  所有人都看了  去吧
You might as well read it. everybody else has. go ahead.
上帝  我感觉被如此地出卖和羞辱
Oh, god, I just feel so betrayed and embarrassed!
只想钻进洞里然后死去
I just want to crawl into a hole and die!
你看  这其实没那么糟糕
Okay. well, you know, this isn't that bad.
只是描绘了一幅
It just paints the picture
浓情蜜意的女人
Of a very affectionate woman,
在非传统地点场合
Who's open to expressing her affection
开放地表达她的情感
In non-traditional locales.
天啊
Oh, god!
电梯里  公园里
Elevators, parks,
电影院里
Movie theaters.
好奇问一下
Out of curiosity,
这里的"地铁"是指交通运输系统
Is this "subway" the transportation system
还是那个叫"地铁"的三明治店?
Or subway the sandwich shop?
三明治店
Sandwich shop.
这是不是违反了卫生许可啊
Doesn't that violate the health code?
没有  在那里我们只是亲热了一下
No, at the sub shop we were only making out.
我是想说
But my point is that
你完全没有理由觉得尴尬啊
You have absolutely no reason to be embarrassed.
真的吗?  你是不是认为我反应太过了?
Really? do you think I overreacted?
-可能有一点  -我确实经常这样  我是个容易过激的人
-maybe a little. -because I do that. I do overreact.
也许我应该打电话跟麦克道歉
Maybe I should call mike and apologize.
你这样反应就变成太不过了
That would be under-reacting.
他确实把卧室里的隐私都暗示出来了
He did break the implied confidentiality of the bedroom.
在你的橱里  电梯  公园  还有在快餐店
And in your case, the elevator, parks and fast food franchise.
你说得对  我就应该说"我跟他玩完了"
You're right. I should just say "i am done with him."
对  你就该这么说  说吧
Yes, you should. go ahead, say it.
但是我还没有给这个男人解释的机会
But I never gave the man a chance to explain.
有什么好解释的
What is there to explain?
都写在这里了
It's all right here.
出卖啊!
The betrayal!
不  你一开始是对的
No, you were right the first time.
这个男人只是用他自己那种很傻的办法爱着我
This is a man who loves me, but in his own stupid way,
只是在向世人宣告他的感受
Which is trying to sw w people how he feels.
我很肯定我没这么说
I'm pretty sure I never said that.
是  你做得更了不起
No, you did better than that.
你让我自己发现了这个事实
You helped me see it on my own.
我真棒啊
Oh, good for me.
你去哪儿
Where are you going?
我去麦克那儿
I'm going over to mike's.
里奥纳德  太感谢你了
Leonard, thank you so much.
没事
Oh, sure.
也许我真是她的同性恋朋友
Huh, maybe I am her gay friend.
霍华德  我想我还需要继续上中文课
Howard, I'm going to nd d another mandarin lesson.
很显然  那些人还是
I obviously didn't make
听不懂我在说什么
My point with those people.
谢尔顿  看在老天的份上
For god's sake, sheldon,
如果你不喜欢陈皮鸡丁
If you don't like the ngngerine chicken,
就不要点陈皮鸡丁
Don't order the tangerine chicken.
我喜欢吃陈皮鸡丁
I like tangerine chicken,
只是他们给我的压根不是陈皮鸡丁
I'm just not getting tangerine chicken.
能不能聊点别的?
Can we please change the subject?
当然
Sure.
我们聊聊你是怎么
Ll us again how you screwed up
让潘妮回到她前男友身边的吧
And got penny back together witherer old boyfriend.
扔你的骰子
Just roll the dice.
"被魔术师俘虏
"enslaved by warlocks.
只有掷出二  四  六才可以离开"
Stay here until you roll two, four or six."
她本来在生他的气的!
She was mad at him!
她本来跟他玩完了!
She was done with him!
这段感情已经是不可能挽回的了
E e relationship was broken beyond repair,
而我跑过去  让他们和好了
And I walked over there, and I fixed it.
天啊  这个故事真是越听越精彩...
Boy, that story gets better every time you hear ..
实际上  我觉得前两个版本
Actually, I thought the first two renditions
要吸引人得多
Were far more compelling.
之前  我对那个叫里奥纳德的角色是报以同情
Previously, I felt sympathy for the leonard character,
现在我只是觉得他很怨妇
Now I just find him to be whiny and annoying.
吃你的陈皮鸡丁去
Eat your tangerine chicken.
我也想吃啊  可我这根本不是陈皮鸡丁
I'd love to, but I don' have tangerine chicken.
非常感谢你愚蠢的建议!
Thank you so much for your stupid advice!
不可思议
Incredible.
你把搞砸的事情又搞砸了
You managed to screw up the screw-up.
我又来了
I'm back.
对不起  刚才我吼你了
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
又不是你的错
It's not your fault.
怎么啦
What happened?
我去麦克那想跟他和好
Well, I went over to mike's to make up with him.
是  不用说  我知道这部分
Yeah. no, I know that part.
但他已经有新欢了
But he had already moved on.
已经?  好快啊
Already? that was quick.
我就是这么对
That's what I said to the woman
那个把脚缠在他脖子上的女人说的
Who had her legs wrapped around his neck!
潘妮  我也很难过
Oh, penny, I am so sorry.
他怎么能这样?!
How could he do that?!
你要知道  你把他80G的IPOD给了...
Well, you know, you did throw an 80-gig ipod...
对呀  他怎么能这样对你
Yeah, no, how could he do that?
我发誓我再也不跟这样的男人交往了
I swear to god I am done with guys like that.
那种身材好  发型帅  有钱的男人
You know, macho with the perfect body and the hair and the money.
是  他们肯定老得很快
Yeah, that must get old quick.
你知道吗  这一次
You know, just once
我真的想和一个
I would like to go out with someone
善良诚实  真正关心我的人约会
Who is nice and honest and who actually cares about me.
我怎么样?
What about me?
你什么怎么样?
What about you what?
你和我约会怎么样?
What about if you went out with me?
你是在约我出去?
Are you asking me out?
是  我是
Um, yes, I am...
在约你出去
Asking you out.
我只是顺着你的话在说...
I was just going off your comment about the nice guy...
-我明白  -诚实啊什么的
No, I know, I got that. you know, and honest.
对啊
Yeah, totally.
...没有什么的
So, but... it's no big deal.
好
Yes.
好什么?
Yes what?
好  我愿意和你去约会
Yes, I will go out with you.
真的吗?
Really?
是
Yeah.
有什么不可以的
Why not?
我已经倾尽所有了
I mean, what do I have to lose?
确实
Yeah.
就该这样想
That's the spirit.
给我看你们的陈皮
Show me your citrus peels.
Gay wo k n ni de jud zi pee.
给我看你们的陈皮
Show me your citrus peels.
Gay wo kan ni de jud zi pee.
-给我看你们的  -谢尔顿?
Show me your... sheldon?
哎呀  吓死我了
Ai yah!xia si wo le
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你有时间吗(second还有次等的意思)
Look, do you have a second?
次等的什么  内衣?
A second what, pair of underwear?
我是在问你是否有空和我聊聊
I was just wondering if I could talk to you.
是关于里奥纳德
It's about leonard.
为什么和我聊
Why me?
为什么不和库萨帕里或者沃尔维茨聊
Why not koothrappali or wolowitz?
拉杰不能和我说话  除非他喝醉了
Well, raj can't talk to me unless he's drunk,
而沃尔维茨  你知道的  他令人恶心
And wolowitz is, you know, disgusting.
是的  我也这么认为
Yes, I suppose he is
我想说的是  你最了解里奥纳德了
All I'm saying is, you know leordrd the best.
不一定
Not necessarily.
我常会惊讶于
I'm often surprised
自己对里奥纳德了解的匮乏
By my lack of familiarity with leonard.
前几天我发现
Just the other day I discovered
他不仅有丝瓜络
He not only has a loofah,
而且还藏起来
He hides it.
你说为什么一个男人会为使用丝瓜络而感到羞耻
Why do you suppose a man would be ashamed of having a loofah?
我个人来说  更乐于让自己的上皮细胞
I, myself, prefer to have my excess epithelial cells
自然脱落  但是我也不责备
Slough off naturally, but I d't condemn
那些试图加速这个过程的人
Those who seek to accelerate the process.
...而且直到最近我才知道
...and until recently I had no idea
尽管他对乳糖过敏
That despite his lactose intolerance,
但他吃少量不含脂的冰淇淋
He can tolerate small amounts of non-fat ice cream
却不会产生在我看来
Without producing a noxious gas that I maintain,
如果适当浓缩  可以成为生化武器的有毒气体
In the right concentration, could be weaponize
里奥纳德可能会回来
Leonard might come home.
能去我屋里聊吗
Can we talk in my apartment?
我们还没聊完?
We're not done?
没有
No.
那好吧
Eh, why not?
反正我们已经穿过镜子了(源于"爱丽丝镜中奇遇记")
We're already through the looking glass anyway.
好  事情是这样的
Okay, so here's the thing...
我想你已经知道  里奥纳德向我开口了
I guess you're aware that leonard asked me out.
他虽然事实上什么都没有说
Well, he didn't actually say anything,
但他回到房间后
But when he came back to the apartment
跳起了一支让人能联想起
He was doing a dance that brought to mind
幻想曲里那只开心河马的舞蹈
The happy hippos in fantasia.
他真好
Oh, that's nice.
无论如何  我想和你说的是
Anyhow, the thing I wanted to talk to you about
你知道  自从我和里奥纳德成为朋友以来...
Is, you know, since leonard and I have become friends...
我只是...
I was just...
你要坐下来吗
You want to sit down?
能那样简单就好了
Oh, I wish it were that simple.
我没在这里待过多久
See, I don't spend much time here,
所以我还从来没有选过一个地方来坐
And so I've never really chosen a place to sit.
那选吧
Well, choose.
这里有许许多多的选择  而且...
There are a number of options, and...
我真的不够熟悉座垫的密度
I'm really not familiar enough with the cushion densities,
气流模式和阳光的散射
Air flow patterns and dispersion of sunlight
来以便做出一个理性的选择
To make an informed choice.
好吧  那你就任意选一处坐
All right.why don't you just pick one at random
如果你不喜欢  下次来再换一个地方
And if you don't like it you can sit somewhere else next time.
不  不  那样太疯狂了
No, no. that's crazy.
你继续说  我一边听一边找
You go ahead and talk while I figure it out.
好吧
Okay.
是这样的
Um, here's the thing.
我已经知道
So I've known for a while now
里奥纳德他有点
That leonard has had
喜欢我...
A little crush on me...
有点喜欢?
A little crush?
我想是的...就像斯巴达王墨涅劳斯
Well, I suppose so--in the same way menelaus
有点喜欢特洛伊的海伦一样
Had a "little crush" on helen of troy.
好吧  我不知道这些人是谁  但...
All right, yeah, I don't really know who they are, but...
墨涅劳斯是阿迦门农的兄弟...
Well, menelaus was the brother of agamemnon...
不用了  不用了  听着
I don't care. I don't care. listen.
我要说的是
The point is,
里奥纳德不是那种经常会和我约会的人
Leonard isn't the kind of guy I usually go out with.
里奥纳德不是那种经常会和任何人约会的人
Leonard isn't the kind of guy anyone usually goes out with.
你是否介意把沙发顺时针旋转30度
Would you be open to rotating the couch clockwise 30 degrees?
不行  我想说的是
No. what I'm saying is
里奥纳德与其他人不同可能是件好事
Leonard might be different in a good way.
很明显  我平时的选择都不怎么的好
Obviously, my usual choices have not worked out so well.
你上一个对库萨帕里来说很好
Your last one worked out well for koothrappali.
他得到了一个免费的ipod
He got a free ipod.
刺眼
Oh, glare.
但换个角度来说  如果和里奥纳德进展不顺利
On the other hand, if things don't go well with leonard,
我可能会失去一个很好的朋友
I risk losing a really good friend.
我意思是  他不会是一时放纵的人
I mean, I'm guessing he's not looking for a fling.
他是那种陷入一段感情后会持续
He's the kind of guy that gets into a relationship
我不知道  可能你会说  光年
For, I don't know, like you would say, light years.
我不会那么说
I would not say that.
没有人
No one
会那么说
Would say that.
光年是一个距离单位而不是一个时间单位
A light year is a unit of distance not time.
谢谢你的说明
Thank you for the clarification.
换
Draft.
人们听到年这个词的时候
See, people hear the word "year"
他们想到的是持续的一段时间
And they think duration.
"尺磅"也有这样的问题...
"foot-pound" has the same problem--
它是一个能量单位  而不是一个重量单位
That's a unit of work, not of weight.
没错  谢谢
Right. thanks.
这是常识性错误
It's common mistake.
这不是我今天犯的第一个错了
Not the first one I've made today.
好
Okay.
我觉得这就是我的座位了
I think this will be my seat.
谢尔顿  你有什么可以说的吗
Sheldon, do you have anything to say
任何内容  你知道
That has anything to do with, you know,
只要和我在说的有关的
What I'm talking about?
好  让我想想
Well, let's see...
我们也许可以参考"薛定谔猫"
We might cononsider schrodinger's cat.
薛定谔
Schrodinger?
是住2楼A座的那个女人吗
Is that the woman in 2a?
不  那位是格洛辛格女士
No, that's mrs. grossinger.
并且她不养猫  她养的是一只墨西哥无毛犬
And she doesn't have a cat, she has a mexican hairless.
超烦人的一种小动物
Annoying little animal. yip, yip, yip, yip.
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
对不起  你又让我跑题了
Sorry, you diverted me.
在1935年  埃尔文·薛定谔
Anyway, in 1935, erwin schrodinger,
尝试去说明在量子物理学中的
In an attempt to explain the copenhagen interpretation
哥本哈根解释
Of quantum physics,
他做了个实验
He proposed an experimen
把一只猫和一小瓶密封好的毒药一起放在盒子里
Where a cat is placed in a box with a sealed vial of poison
毒药瓶随时会破裂
That will break open at a random time.
好  除非你打开盒子
Now, since no one knows when
不然没人知道毒药是否
Or if the poison has been released,
或者是何时已经被释放了
Until the box is opened,
因此我们认为猫或活或死都是可以的
The cat can be thought of as both alive and dead.
对不起  我没听明白
I'm sorry. I don't get the point.
你当然不会明白  我还没说呢
Wellofof course you don't get it; I haven't made it yet.
你只有靠第六感才能明白了
You'd have to be psychic to get it,
而事实是根本就没有"第六感"这个东西
And there's no such thing as "psychic."
谢尔顿  你到底想说什么?
Sheldon, what's the point?!
就好像"薛定谔猫"
Just like schrodinger's cat,
现在你和里奥纳德潜在的可能
Your potential relationship with leonard right now
既可以被认为是美好的也可以是不好的
Can be thought of as both good and bad.
只有当你打开盒子
It is only by opening the box
你才知道到底是哪一种
That you'll find out which it is.
明白了  你是说我应该先跟里奥纳德处处看
Okay, so you're saying I should go out with leonard.
不不  不不
No, no, no, no, no.
我再说一遍吧
Let me start again.
在1935年  埃尔文·薛定谔...
In 1935, erwin schrodinger...
那儿有俩座
Two seats right there.
长寿石灰?
Chung shu shway?
谢谢
Shay shay.
谢尔顿  我想我办错了件事
Sheldon, I think I've made a mistake.
我知道
I can see that.
除非你是在备战马拉松
Unless you're planning on running a marathon,
不然填塞陷儿和土豆泥都要
Choosing both stuffing and mashed potatoes
简直就是淀粉摄入过量
Is a starch-filled redundancy.
不  是关于潘妮的
No, it's about penny.
关于潘妮的错误
A mistake involving penny.
好吧  我得缩小范围了
Okay, you'll have to narrow it down.
我觉得今天晚上我不能跟她去约会
I don't think I can go out with her tonight.
那就别去
Then don't.
别人一般会说"为什么不去"
Other pelele would say "why not?"
别人可能比较感兴趣
Other people might be interested.
反正我还是要说
I'm going to talk anyway.
我猜你也是
I assumed you would.
现在我真的要和潘妮去约会了
Now that I'm actually about to go out with penny,
我反而并不激动  我反胃
I'm not excited--i'm nauseous.
那你的食物就是选对了
Ah, then your meal choice is appropriate.
淀粉能吸收对于呕吐起作用的
Starch absorbs fluid which reduces the amount of vomit
催吐物质
Available for violent expulsion.
-好吧  -你还犯了
Right. you also made
一个文法上的错误
A common grammatical mistake.
你说的是"反胃的"  其实你想说"让人作呕的"
You said "nauseous," when you meant "nauseated."
你接着说
But go on.
谢尔顿  这次约会很可能就是我唯一的机会
Sheldon, this date is probably my one chance with penny.
我如果搞砸了怎么办?
What happens if I blow it?
好  假设我们按你说的前提
Well, if we accept your premise
并且承认潘妮就是上帝安排给你的另一半
And also accept the highly improbable assumption
这个极不可能的假设
That penny is the only woman in the world for you,
那我们从逻辑上可以得出的结论是
Then we can logically conclude that the result
如果你搞砸这次约会  后果就是
Of blowing it would  be that you end up
你将会孤独  辛酸地终老  并且没有后代
A lonely, bitter old man with no progeny.
我脑中突然浮现了史酷比动画片里
The image of any number of evil lighthouse keepers
一群邪恶的灯塔管理员的画面
From scooby-doo cartoons comes to mind.
你这是在捣乱
You're not helping.
好吧  我怎么回答你
All right, what respon on my part
才能赶紧结束这个话题呢?
Would bring this conversation to a speedy conclusion?
你就告诉我该不该去赴约
Tell me whether or not to go through with the date.
薛定谔猫
Scododinger's cat.
太聪明了
Wow,that's brilliant.
你听起来很吃惊啊
You sound surprised.
猴子睡在里头
Ho-tsu shway zai li-toe.
好啊
Hi.
好
进来
Come on in.
谢谢
Thank you.
你真漂亮
You look very nice.
谢谢  你也是
Thank you. so do you.
我定了座位  8点
I made an 8:00 reservation.
好啊  太好了
Okay, yeah, great.
听着
Listen, um...
也许我们应该先谈谈
Maybe we should talk first.
好
Okay.
但是在你说之前
But before you say anything,
你听说过薛定谔猫吗
Have you ever heard of schrodinger's cat?
事实上  我听过太多薛定谔猫了
Actually, I've heard far too much about schrodinger's cat.
好
Good.
好啦  看来猫还是活的
All right, the cat's alive.
我们去吃饭吧
L's go to dinner.
鼻涕在哪儿  鼻涕
Bee ti tsai nar! bee ti!
擤干净鼻涕  快走快走
Xing gan jing bi ti hou quai zoui.
这不是柳丁脚踏车
Zhe bu shi lui ding jiao ta che!
简直是疯子  给我报警
Crazy man. call the police!
不必打给图书馆
Bu bie da gei tu shu guan.
鼻涕在哪儿
Bee ti tsai nar!
蛮牛在我床上
Man niu zai wo chuang shang!
很多很多蛮牛
Hen duo hen duo man niu!
哎呀
Ai yah!